computervalley.ca 2011-06-20

# Privacy Notice : Online Computer Store Canada | Computer Store Online, Computer Parts Store | Computer Shop, Computer Hardware Store | Computer Valley â€“ New Products

**Our Privacy Commitment**  
At ComputerValley.ca we know how important it is to protect your personal information. When you are shopping with us online we want to make every customer experience safe and secure. In keeping with that goal, we have developed this Privacy Policy to explain our practices for the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information.

This Policy applies to our Web Site and all other channels in which ComputerValley.ca collects and uses your personal information.

 ** _What Information does ComputerValley.ca Collect?_** _  
_At ComputerValley.ca, we collect two types of information: personal information and non-personal information. The types of information we collect depend on the nature of your interaction with us.

Personal information 

  * Personal information is information that can identify an individual or information about an identifiable individual. We may collect personal information such as:
    * your contact information – e.g., name, postal address, telephone number, and email address;
    * your personal preferences – e.g., product wish lists, language preferences, and marketing consent; and
    * your transaction information – e.g., products purchased, method of payment, amount paid, and credit or debit card number.

Non-personal information 

  * Non-personal information does not identify you as an individual. For example:
    * we may ask you for your postal code to assist us with planning our flyer distribution;
    * we may collect certain non-personal data when you visit our Web Sites, such as the type of browser you are using or the referring URL; or
    * we may collect and summarize customer information in a non-personal, aggregate format for statistical and research purposes. We may, for example, summarize our data to determine that a certain percentage of contest entrants are male, aged 18 to 25.

All references to “Web Sites” in this Privacy Policy mean www.computervalley.ca or other ComputerValley.ca provided Web sites.

You may choose not to provide us with your personal information. However, if you make this choice we may not be able to provide you with the product, service, or information that you requested. For example, we can only offer you a ComputerValley.ca credit card if you have provided us with certain financial information. 

**_How is Your Personal Information Used?_** _  
_ComputerValley.ca may use your personal information for a number of different business purposes, for example to:

  * fulfill your specific requests for products, services or information; 
  * provide customer support to assist you with your questions or complaints; 
  * conduct surveys in order to improve our services; 
  * measure and improve the effectiveness of our Web Sites or our marketing endeavors; 
  * detect and protect against fraud and error; 
  * track and analyze your purchases and preferences to better understand your product and service needs and eligibility; 
  * tailor our online content or in-store offerings based on your preferences; 
  * if you ask us, to offer and promote additional products and services we offer; and 
  * for other purposes as described in this Privacy Policy. 

**_Your Consent_** _  
_ComputerValley.ca will collect, use, or disclose your personal information only with your knowledge and consent, except where required or permitted by law. When you choose to provide us with your personal information you consent to the use of your personal information as identified in this Privacy Policy and as may be further identified at the time of collection.

Express Consent 

  * Sometimes you will be asked to give your express consent, such as by checking a box to indicate your consent to receive marketing communications, or by providing your signature to indicate your acceptance of the use and disclosure terms presented on an application form.

Implied Consent 

  * Other times, we may obtain your consent implicitly when we can reasonably conclude that you’ve given consent by some action you have taken or an action you have decided not to take. Generally, this occurs where the purpose for use of your personal information would be reasonably apparent to you.

Withdrawing Your Consent 

  * You may notify us at any time that you wish to withdraw or change your consent to our use and disclosure or your information. We will accommodate your request subject to legal and contractual restrictions related to your transactions. 
  * If you have "opted in" or subscribed to one of our newsletters or mailing lists, we will always provide you the opportunity to "opt out" or unsubscribe. For example, each e-newsletter we send to you will include a link or other method to unsubscribe or decline further e-newsletters. 

**_Information ComputerValley.ca Collects Directly from You_** _  
_Listed here are some further examples of the ways that we collect personal information directly from you and how we use it.

 **Returns and Exchanges**  
Our goal is to ensure that you are completely satisfied with your purchase and to this end, ComputerValley.ca offers a Return Policy. For ComputerValley.ca to continue to offer our Return Policy, we ask for personal information such as your name, address, and telephone number for the purposes of detecting and preventing fraud. You may also be asked to produce photo ID for verification purposes only.

 **ReClaim Insurance Replacement**  
When working with our ReClaim Consultants to replace goods that are covered under your insurance policy, we will need some basic information, such as your contact information, insurance claim number, and the name of your claim adjuster, so we can process your quote in a timely manner and bill your insurance company directly for you.

 **Purchase Follow-Up and Surveys**  
Following a purchase from some of our departments we may send you a follow-up letter to thank you for your business, or we may contact you to ensure that you are completely satisfied with the delivery, setup, or installation of your new product. We may use contact information collected online, or via our call centre to conduct occasional surveys and other customer research. These surveys are entirely voluntary and you may easily decline to participate.

 **Our Web Sites**  
Our Web Sites can be browsed anonymously. However, to engage in certain special features or functions of our Web Sites, or to order products and services from our Web Sites, you may be asked to provide certain personal information, such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone number, or credit card information. We use this information to create your account, contact and correspond with you about your order, respond to your inquiries, and monitor functions of our Web Sites that you choose to use, such as online forums.

 **Online Forums and Customer Reviews**  
Certain pages of our Web Sites, such as “Community Forum”, facilitate interactive discussions between users and ComputerValley.ca staff or agents acting on our behalf regarding products and services available for purchase through the Web Sites. The Customer Review functionality is provided as a rating system that offers you the chance to share your thoughts on a product. These public forums and reviews are accessible to all Web Site visitors so please use discretion when posting information to them and do not post personal information.

 **Sign-Up for Newsletters or Updates**  
ComputerValley.ca also offers a variety of newsletters and promotional communications. Should you choose to enrol we will collect your contact information, such as name and email address. This information will only be used to send you the newsletter and promotional announcements that you have requested. You may “unsubscribe” at any time by using the unsubscribe link included in the footer of the newsletter or by using the unsubscribe link included below under the heading “Unsubscribe”. Our subscriber list is never sold or rented to other parties.

 **Participate in a Contest or Promotion**  
From time to time, we may run contests or promotions. If you participate, you may be asked for contact information as well as additional optional survey information (for example, product preferences). Personal information from contest entries will be used only to administer the contest and contact you if you win. For research and analysis purposes, we may also summarize contest survey information in a manner that no longer identifies individual participants. All contests and promotions are subject to this Privacy Policy and the rules that will be available with each particular campaign. Some contests are conducted by third parties and will be subject to the third party’s policies.

 **Tell a Friend**  
While visiting our Web Sites you may choose to use the “Tell a Friend” tool which allows you to inform a friend about products of interest to you. The information you provide will be used to send a one-time email to your friend, inviting them to our Web Sites. We will not add your friend to a mailing list and will not send them further email unless they choose to receive such communications from us. When using the “Tell a Friend” tool you are contacting your friend directly and as such you acknowledge that you are responsible for this correspondence and not ComputerValley.ca. If you provide us with personal information concerning another individual (e.g., email address), you represent and warrant that you have obtained all necessary consents from that individual to enable us to use that personal information for the identified purpose.

 **Subscription Services and Activations**  
ComputerValley.ca may offer activation of certain products and services like cellular plans, satellite services, or Internet services. These activations may require that certain contact and financial information be collected and provided to the respective service providers as part of the activation process. For example, a cellular carrier may need to perform a credit check prior to activation so a government-issued ID number and your credit card number may be provided to the carrier for that purpose.

 **Call Centre**  
ComputerValley.ca operates customer support call centre to accept and address your questions, concerns, or complaints. When you contact our call centre, we may ask for personal information to help us respond to your inquiry or to verify your identity. For example if you have a question about the status of a recent online order, we will ask for personal information to verify that you are the account holder. We may also monitor or record your telephone discussions with our customer support representatives for training purposes and to ensure service quality.

 ** _Information ComputerValley.ca Collects Automatically_** _  
_In some cases, we automatically collect certain information.

 **Our Web Sites**  
When using our Web Sites, we may collect the Internet Protocol (IP) address of your computer, the IP address of your Internet Service Provider, the date and time you access our Web Sites, the Internet address of the Web site from which you linked directly to our Web Site, the operating system you are using, the sections of the Web Site you visit, the Web Site pages read and images viewed, and the content you download from the Web Site. This information is used for Web Site and system administration purposes and to improve the Web Sites.

 **Cookies**  
The Web Site uses "cookies", a technology that installs a small amount of information on a Web Site user's computer to permit the Web Site to recognize future visits using that computer. Cookies enhance the convenience and use of the Web Site. For example, the information provided through cookies is used to recognize you as a previous user of the Web Site (so you do not have to enter your language preference every time), to offer personalized Web page content and information for your use, to track your activity at the Web Site, to respond to your needs, and to otherwise facilitate your Web Site experience. You may choose to decline cookies if your browser permits, but doing so may affect your use of the Web Site and your ability to access certain features of the Web Site or engage in transactions through the Web Site.

 **Web Site Tracking Information**  
We may use web beacons or pixel tags to compile tracking information reports regarding Web Site user demographics, Web Site traffic patterns, and Web Site purchases. We may then provide these reports to advertisers and others. None of the tracking information in these reports can be connected to the identities or other personal information of individual users. For our own research purposes we may link tracking information with personal information voluntarily provided by Web Site users. Once such a link is made, all of the linked information is treated as personal information and will be used and disclosed only in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

 **Links to Other Web Sites**  
Our Web Site may contain links to other Web sites or Internet resources which are provided solely for your convenience and information. When you click on one of those links you are contacting another Web site or Internet resource. ComputerValley.ca has no responsibility or liability for, or control over, those other Web sites or Internet resources or their collection, use and disclosure of your personal information. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of those other Web sites to learn how they collect and use your personal information.

 ** _Data on Returned Product_** _  
_When returning products which may contain stored or recorded personal information, like computers, PDAs, digital cameras, etc., you are responsible for deleting or removing all personal information and media from your product before you return it. ComputerValley.ca is not responsible for any personal data or media left behind.

 ** _Supplementing information_** _  
_From time to time we may supplement information you give us with information from other sources, such as information validating your address or other available information you have provided us. This is to help us maintain the accuracy of the information we collect and to help us provide better service.

 ** _Does ComputerValley.ca Share Your Information?_** _  
_ComputerValley.ca does not sell or rent our customers’ personal information to any other party. However, in the normal course of business we may share some of your personal information within our corporate family and with third parties acting on our behalf or as permitted or required by law.

Some of these operations may result in personal information collected by ComputerValley.ca being stored or processed outside of Canada and, as a result, your personal information may be accessible to law enforcement and regulatory authorities in accordance with the law of these foreign jurisdictions.

 **Service Providers**  
ComputerValley.ca may use third parties to manage one of more aspects of our business operations, including the processing or handing of personal information. When we do use an outside company, we use contractual or other appropriate means to ensure that your personal information is used in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy.

For example, we may share personal information with third parties to perform services on our behalf such as: fulfilling online orders, processing non-cash payments, sending marketing communications, servicing products, conducting research surveys, verifying and validating information that you have provided to us, delivering products, and providing customer support services.

ComputerValley.ca has taken precautions to prevent the fraudulent use of your information on our Web Sites. ComputerValley.ca has adopted industry standard authentication procedures to ensure your protection while shopping with us online. This includes, but is not limited to, contacting financial institutions or credit reporting agencies to ensure the authenticity of your credit card and to validate your credit card billing information.

 **Information Shared Amongst ComputerValley.ca, its Corporate Parents, Affiliates, Subsidiaries and Divisions**  
ComputerValley.ca may share personal information gathered on our Web Sites with ComputerValley.ca retail stores (and vice versa) and amongst our corporate parents, subsidiaries, affiliates or divisions for internal business purposes in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If ComputerValley.ca shares your information within its corporate family, we will ensure that your information continues to be used only in accordance with this Privacy Policy and your expressed choices.

 **Product Safety Recalls**  
In the event we receive notice from a manufacturer of a product safety recall, we may provide your contact information, limited to name, address, and telephone number, to the manufacturer so that they may notify you of the recall and supply details of any replacement or repair programs. This transfer or your contact information will occur only for recalls that may impact your personal safety or impair the functionality of the product you purchased from us.

 **Sale or Transfer of all or part of ComputerValley.ca**  
Any information we have about you may be transferred or disclosed to a purchaser or prospective purchaser in the event of a sale, assignment, or other transfer of all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to ensure that the transferee uses your information in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy.

 **Legal Disclosure**  
ComputerValley.ca may disclose your information as permitted or required by law. For example, we may be compelled to release information by a court of law or other person or entity with jurisdiction to compel production of such information. If we have reasonable grounds to believe information could be useful in the investigation of improper or unlawful activity, we may disclose information to law enforcement agencies or other appropriate investigative bodies.

 ** _How does ComputerValley.ca Protect Your Information?_** _  
_The security of your personal information is a high priority for ComputerValley.ca. We maintain appropriate safeguards and current security standards to protect your personal information, whether recorded on paper or captured electronically, against unauthorized access, disclosure, or misuse. For example, electronic records are stored in secure, limited-access servers; we employ technological tools like firewalls and passwords; and we ensure our employees are trained on the importance of maintaining the security and confidentiality of personal information.

Although we cannot take responsibility for any theft, misuse, unauthorized disclosure, loss, alteration or destruction of data by a third party, we take reasonable precautions to prevent such unfortunate occurrences.

 ** _How Can You Verify Your Information?_** _  
_You may check your information to verify, update, or correct it, and to have any obsolete information removed. If you created an account on one of our Web Sites, you can access and change your online account profile yourself. You can also ask to review any of the information that we have retained, how we have used it, and to whom we have disclosed it at any time by contacting us as indicated below under the heading "Contacting ComputerValley.ca". Subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law, and provided we can authenticate your identity, you will be given reasonable access to your personal information, and will be entitled to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and to have it amended as appropriate. You may also ask us to change your preferences regarding how we use or disclose your information, or let us know that you do not wish to receive any further communication from us.

 ** _When is Your Information Removed?_** _  
_We keep your information only as long as we need it for legitimate business purposes and to meet any legal requirements. We have retention standards that meet these parameters. We destroy your information when it is no longer needed, or we remove your personally identifiable information to render it anonymous.

 ** _Contacting ComputerValley.ca_** _  
_ComputerValley.ca is responsible for all personal information under its control. Our Privacy Manager is accountable for ComputerValley.ca's compliance with the principles described here. If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about the privacy practices of our organization please contact us at the following:

Email:

| 

[Click here](mailto:info@computervalley.ca) (please read the Important Reminder below)  
  
---|---  
  
|   

|   

We will respond to your request or investigate your concern as quickly as we can, but no later than 30 days from the date of receipt of your query.

 _Important Reminder about email communications:_  
Please remember that email sent over the public Internet is not secure. If you send an email directly to us from your own email account the contents will not be encrypted. We strongly recommend that you do not send sensitive information (like a credit card number) to us via unencrypted email. ComputerValley.ca is not responsible for any transmission by you of any personal information over the public Internet.

 ** _Unsubscribe_** _  
_If you no longer wish to be contacted regarding promotions, new product and entertainment releases and how to make the most of the latest technology[ click here](http://www.computervalley.ca/index.php?main_page=unsubscribe).

 ** _Will this Privacy Policy Change? Last Update: November, 2009_** _  
_To accommodate changes in our services, changes in technology, and legal developments, this Privacy Policy may change over time without notice to you. We may add, change, or remove portions of the Privacy Policy when we feel it is appropriate to do so. We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy periodically. Each time you submit personal information or use our services you agree to be bound by the then current terms of the Privacy Policy. Whenever we update the Privacy Policy we will change the date to indicate when the changes were made.
